One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
Bell-mère
بيلمير-سان
Alright.
حسنٌ
Let's hear this reason, then.
لنسمع السبب إذًا
I'll pass.
أمتنع عنه
H-Hey!
!عـ-على مهلك
I don't care about her past.
لا يهمني ماضيها
Where are you going, Luffy?
إلى أين تمضي يا لوفي؟
For a walk.
لأتمشى
A-A walk?! You're not gonna listen to this?!
تتمشى؟ ألن تنصت لهذا؟
Nah. Pass.
لا، أمتنع عنه
What's with him?
ما خطبه؟
Don't mind him. That's just how he is.
دعكِ منه فهذه طبيعته
We'll hear you out.
نحن سننصت إليكِ
Though I doubt it'll make much of a difference.
مع أني أشك أن إنصاتنا سيغير شيئًا
Yeah! I'll listen, too!
نعم، سأنصت أنا أيضًا
I wanna know what's happening on this island!
أريد معرفة ما يجري في هذه الجزيرة
Me, too! I want to know everything about Nami!
وأنا أيضًا، أريد معرفة كل شيءٍ عن نامي-سان
He's out like a light.
نام سلفًا
Don't sleep right after saying that!
!لا تنم فور قولك ذلك
I see.
فهمت
So this is why Nami is having such a hard time.
لهذا تواجه نامي وقتًا عصيبًا إذًا
I fell asleep...?
...يبدو أني غفوتُ
Huh?
ماذا؟
Nojiko?
نوجيكو؟
Where could she have gone?
أين ذهبت يا تُراها؟
Just a little more, Bell-mère.
قليلًا بعد يا بيلمير-سان
Just a little more, and we'll have it all back.
قليلًا بعد وستعود الأوضاع إلى ما كانت عليه
Cocoyashi Village, the tangerine orchard,
...قرية كوكوياشي، بستان اليوسفي
and even my dream!
!وحتى حلمي
It took eight years...
...استغرقني هذا ثماني سنين
Nami (8 Years Ago)
(نامي (قبل 8 سنين
It's done...
...أنهيتها
It's done!
!أنهيتها
Now I just need to check that book...
...والآن عليّ تفقد ذلك الكتاب فحسب
Oh!
!ويحي
Nami!
!نا-تشان
What's wrong?
ما الخطب؟
Nothing!
!لا شيء
Nothing at all!
!لا شيء إطلاقًا
Oh, my!
!ويحي
Damn it, Nami!
!تبًّا يا نامي
Not again!
!ليس مجددًا
Oh? You did it again, Nami?
أفعلتها ثانيةً يا نا-تشان؟
Let go!
!أفعلتني
You just never learn!
!أنتِ لا تتعلمين أبدًا
I'm not a cat!
!أنا لست قطة
You idiot!
!أيتها الحمقاء
Genzo (8 Years Ago)
(غينزو (قبل 8 سنين
How many times do I have to tell you not to steal?!
كم مرةً أخبرتكِ أنَّ السرقة ليست أمرًا حميدًا؟
It's not our fault we're poor!
فقرُنَا ليس ذنبي
Cheapskate!
!أيها البخيل
Bell-mère!
!بيلمير
Your no-good cat's been at it again!
!كرّرت قطتكِ الفاسدة فعلتها
Bell-mère Nami and Nojiko's Foster Mother
بيلمير الأم الحاضنة لنامي ونوجيكو
What is it? Pipe down!
!ماذا تريد؟ ما أزعجك
Oh!
،عجبًا
Welcome home, Nami!
!أهلًا بعودتكِ يا نامي
I'm back!
!لقد عدت
Look! This is the umpteenth time!
!انظري، هذه المرة المليون
She's infamous in the village now!
!انحطت سمعتها في القرية
Oh? Is that so?
وما بذلك؟
Surely even you've stolen something before, Mr. Gen?
أليس لديك سوابق في السرقة يا غين-سان؟
You're the reason she acts like this!
!إنك سبب تصرفاتها
I'm just kidding!
!أمزح
Look, I get it.
فهمت مقصدك
You covered the cost, right?
دفعت لها، صحيح؟
B-Bell-mère...
...بـ-بيلمير
I can't thank you enough.
أشكرك
Money's a bit tight right now.
لا مال لديّ حاليًا
I'll pay you back later...
...سأدفع لك لاحقًا
with my body.
بجسدي...
I d-didn't mean it l-like that!
!لـ-لم أ-أعني هذا
You're beet red!
!احمرّ وجهك
Oh? And why are you laughing?
عجبي، ما بالك تضحكين؟
I'm sorry!
!أعتذر
But I really wanted this book!
!لكني أردتُ الكتاب حقًّا
If you wanted it, why didn't you just tell me?
لمَ لمْ تخبريني بما أنك تريدينه؟
You wouldn't have bought it for me anyway...
...ما كنتِ لتشترينه لي على أيّ حال
Of course I would have!
!كنتُ لأشتريه طبعًا
We've got some money stashed away.
بحوزتنا مالٌ مخبأ
But the villagers said that the weather's been so good lately,
لكن أهل القرية قالوا إنّ الطقس صافٍ هذه الأيام
any old field will grow tons of tangerines.
بحيث إنه يمكن زراعة اليوسفيّ في أيّ حقل
We can't get a good price for ours, and they won't sell anyway.
وما كانت خاصتنا لتُباع كثيرًا لأن قيمتها لا ترتفع
They can mind their own business!
وما دخلهم في شؤون الغير؟
You're so dumb, Nami!
!أنتِ مغفلة حقًّا يا نامي
Nojiko (8 Years Ago)
(نوجيكو (قبل 8 سنين
I would've stolen it way better!
!كنتُ لأسرقه ببراعةٍ أكثر
I said no stealing!
ألم أقل لا للسرقة؟
I was just joking!
!كنتُ أمزح فحسب
That hurts!
!هذا مؤلم
But you know, one thing's for sure!
،لكن ثمّة أمرٌ مؤكّد
You really draw some amazing maps, Nami!
!الخرائط التي ترسمينها مذهلة حقًّا يا نامي
First you learned to draw sea charts, and now land maps!
!تعلّمتِ في البداية رسم البحر والآن خرائط البر
This is a map of this island, isn't it?!
هذه خريطة هذه الجزيرة، صحيح؟
No one would ever think someone your age drew this!
!ما كان أحدٌ ليتوقع أن فتاةً صغيرةً رسمتها
I've been studying navigation, too!
!إنني أدرس الملاحة أيضًا
Even navigation?!
حتى الملاحة؟
That's Nami's dream, after all!
!إنه حلمها بعد كل شيء
Yeah!
!نعم
I'm gonna use my navigation skills to sail all the world's seas!
سأستخدم مهاراتي في الملاحة لأجوب بحار العالم
And then I'll make a map of everything I see!
!وبعدها سأصنع خريطةً فيها كل ما أراه
That means this map of the island is the first step towards your dream!
خريطة الجزيرة هذه هي خطوتكِ الأولى صوب حلمك إذًا؟
Yeah!
!نعم
A map of the world, huh?
خريطة العالم إذًا؟
Nami! Someday, your dream will come true!
!ستحققين حلمكِ يومًا يا نامي
I just know it!
!كلي ثقةٌ بكِ
Hey, Bell-mère.
بالمناسبة يا بيلمير-سان
You haven't been eating lately.
...لا أراكِ تأكلين هذه الأيام
I'm eating tangerines, aren't I?
ألستُ آكل اليوسفي؟
I'm on a diet right now!
!إني أتبع حمية فحسب
I don't need any food, either.
...لا أحتاج طعامًا أيضًا
Since when are you watching your figure?
متى صرتِ مهتمةً بجسمكِ؟
Kids need to eat right!
!على الأطفال أن يأكلوا جيِّدًا
Stop lying!
!كفاكِ كذبًا
You aren't eating because we don't have any money, right?
لا طعام لكِ لأن لا مال لدينا، صحيح؟
Really?!
حقًّا؟
You're suffering so that we can–
...أنتِ تعانين من أجلنا
I'm on a diet!
!بل حمية
You shouldn't underestimate the rejuvenating power of tangerines!
!لا تستخفي بقوة اليوسفي التجميلية
They're the reason I still have such glowing skin at the age of thirty!
!يُعزى الفضل لها لتمتعي بهذه البشرة النضرة في سن الثلاثين
But your hands are yellow.
.لكن يديكِ شاحبتين
Just shut up and eat!
!اخرسي وكلي فحسب
Here you go, Nami! It's done!
!ها نحن ذا يا نامي، انهيتها
It's Bell-mère's own haute couture brand!
!إنها ماركة بيلمير الخاصة بالأزياء الراقية
Another hand-me-down from Nojiko?
مخلّفات نوجيكو ثانيةً؟
Now, now!
!هيا، هيا
It looks great on you, Nami!
!يناسبك
This lion used to be a sunflower!
!كان هذا الأسد عبّاد شمس
That's just how it goes!
!ما باليد حيلة
You're two years younger than I am!
!أنتِ أصغر مني بعامين
Age has nothing to do with it!
!لا علاقة للسن بالأمر
I want new clothes, too!
!أريد ثيابًا جديدة فحسب
Mine are old clothes, too, you know!
!حتى ثيابي قديمة
You get my stuff 'cause you're my baby sister!
!تحصلين على ثيابي لأنكِ أختي الصغرى
But I'm not even your real sister!
!لكني لستُ أختكِ الفعلية
We're not related by blood!
!فلا تربطنا صلة دم
Nami!
!نامي
Bell-mère!
!بيلمير-سان
So what if you're not blood-related?!
وماذا إلّم تربطكما صلة دم؟
Don't say something that stupid ever again!
!إيّاكِ قول أمر طائش كهذا ثانيةً
Wh-Whatever...
...لـ-لا يهم
It's not like you're our real mom, anyway!
!لستِ أمنا الفعلية أيضًا
You'd be better off without us, wouldn't you?!
لكان حالكِ أفضل من دوننا، صحيح؟
That way, you'd have enough to eat!
،لكان لديكِ ما يكفي للغذاء
You could buy all the clothes you want! You could be free!
!ولكان بوسعك شراء ما أردتِ ثيابًا، لكنتِ حرَّةً
I wish...
...يا ليت
I wish someone richer had adopted me instead!
!يا ليت أحدًا أغنى منكِ تبناني
Is...
...هـ
that so?
هكذا إذًا؟
Fine, then! Do what you want!
!فليكن، افعلي ما يحلو لكِ
If you hate this house so much, feel free to go live somewhere else!
!إن كنتِ تكرهين هذا البيت بهذا القدر، فارحلي حيثما تشائين
Stop it, you two!
!توقّفا أنتما الاثنتان
Fine! I'm leaving!
!سأرحل
Nami!
!نامي
Bell-mère...
...بيلمير-سان
The three of us are a family!
!نحن الثلاثة عائلة
I bet Nami feels the same way!
!أنا واثقة أنّ نامي تشعر هكذا أيضًا
She didn't mean what she said!
!فما أظنها قصدت ما قالته قبلًا
You're a good girl, Nojiko.
أنتِ فتاة صالحة يا نوجيكو
That was real immature of me.
كان تصرّفًا يفتقر للنضج مني
Could you go bring Nami back for me?
هلّا ذهبتِ وأعدتِ نامي من أجلي
I'll have a super awesome dinner ready before you get back!
!سأحضّر عشاءً في غاية اللذة ريثما تعودان
Okay!
!حسنًا
Cocoyashi Village
قرية كوكوياشي
Alright, ma'am! How about this much?
!حسنٌ يا سيدتي، سأخفض الثمن بهذا القدر
What? Can't you do better than that?
!ماذا؟ خفضه أكثر قليلًا
Right over here! Come see our low prices!
!تعالوا هنا، لدينا تخفيضات، تخفيضات
You can't beat my fruit when it comes to freshness!
لا يمكنكم التغلب على بضاعتي حين يتعلق الأمر بالنضارة
So, coming here from the edge of the village is "running away"?
أتُعدّين المجيء إلى هنا من ضواحي البلدة هروبًا؟
Must be pretty convenient!
!هذا مريحٌ بالتأكيد
Here. Drink up before it gets cold!
!اشربيه قبل أن يبرد
Bell-mère would be happier if we were gone.
كانت بيلمير-سان لتكون أسعد برحيلنا
Why do you think that?
لِمَ تظنّين هذا؟
Having two kids costs a lot of money,
...يكلّف الاعتناء بطفلين مالًا كثيرًا
and everyone in the village hates her because of me.
...كما يكرهها أهل القرية بسببي
You're old enough to think about others now, huh?
كبرتِ بما يكفي لتراعي حال الغير إذًا؟
Don't worry.
لا تقلقي
She was a pretty infamous brat when she was your age, too.
في سنِّكِ كانت شقيةً شائنة السمعة
Really? Bell-mère?
بيلمير-سان؟
She's still quite an infamous brat in the villagers' eyes!
وما زالت شقيَّةً في نظر القرويين
Imagine how surprised we were when she suddenly declared,
تخيلي دهشتنا حين أعلنت فجأةً أنها ستنضم للبحرية
A Marine?!
البحرية؟
Bell-mère was a Marine?!
أكانت بيلمير-سان في البحرية؟
Yeah...
.أجل
"Pirates have to pay for slaughtering innocent people!"
...على القراصنة أن يُجازوا على إيذاء الأبرياء
With those words, she left the village.
غادرت القرية بعد قول هذه الكلمات
Just as she thought her time had finally come...
...حين اعتقدت أن أجلها حان
Well... I guess this is it...
...لا يهم
Is that your baby sister?
أهذه أختك الصغيرة؟
Nuh-uh. I dunno who she is.
لا، لا أعرفها
She has no idea what's going on...
...لا فكرة لها عما يجري
Nami, that girl...
...تلك الفتاة
was you.
كانت أنت...
When she saw you, Bell-mère mustered up the will to live again.
عندما رأتكما استجمعت بيلمير إرادتها للعيش
It is a boat! I knew it!
!إنه قارب كما توقعت
On a stormy night like tonight?! Who the hell could it be?!
في ليلة عاصفة كهذه؟ من تراه يكون؟
Doctor!
!طبيب
Get the doctor!
!استدعوا طبيبًا
Bell-mère? Is that you, Bell-mère?!
بيلمير؟ أهذه أنتِ يا بيلمير؟
Bell-mère!
!بيلمير
What in the world happened?!
!ما هذا؟
Who are these–
...من هاتان
Doctor! They have terrible fevers!
!طبيب! إنهما تعانيان من حمى شديدة
They're exhausted from the storm!
!أُرهقتا كليًّا من شدة العاصفة
What?!
!ماذا؟
R-Right, got it!
!حسنًا
But we need to tend to those nasty wounds of yours, too!
!علينا أن نعتني بجراحكِ الجسيمة أيضًا
Forget about that! Just hurry!
!أسرع فحسب
Please! Don't let them die!
!أترجى ألا تدعهما تموتان
Save them!
!أنقذهما
I beg of you!
!أترجاك
A delinquent like you... What did you just say?!
كيف لجانحةٍ مثلكِ... ماذا قلتِ توًّا؟
I said that I'm going to be their mother.
قلت إنني سأصبح أمهما
You can't!
!إيّاكِ
Don't do it!
!لا تفعلي
A punk like you can't possibly raise children!
!مستحيلٌ على رعاعةٍ مثلكِ أن تعتني بأطفال
L-Listen to me! Give them to a government institution!
!ا-اعملي بنصيحتي وسلّميهما إلى مؤسسة حكومية
I've already made up my mind!
!اتخذتُ قراري سلفًا
I'm an adult now, too.
أنا راشدة الآن أيضًا
I was even a Marine.
حتى أني كنتُ في البحرية
I've tried to become more of a decent human being.
حاولتُ أن أصير إنسانةً أكثر استقامة
I'm going to be responsible for raising these kids.
سأتحمّل مسؤولية تربية هاتين الطفلتين
I'll raise them to be good people.
سأربّيهما لتصيرا امرأتين صالحتين لا تنهزمان أمام عصرنا
I'm going to live on with these girls.
سأعيش مع هاتين الطفلتين
Nami and Nojiko saved my life.
نامي ونوجيكو منحتا لي الحياة
The bond you three have runs far deeper than blood.
الصلة بينكم أعمق بكثيرٍ من صلة دم
Nami! I thought you'd be here!
!نامي! توقعتُ أنكِ ستكونين هنا
N-Nojiko!
!نـ-نوجيكو
Bell-mère is waiting for us!
!بيلمير-سان تنتظرنا
She's making a yummy dinner!
!وهي تعدّ عشاءً لذيذًا
Okay!
!حسنًا
I bet it's your favorite!
!أُراهن أنه طعامكِ المفضل
Omelets with tangerine sauce!
!العجّة مع صلصة اليوسفيّ
Yahoo!
!مرحى
– Yay! Omelets!
!مرحى، العجّة
Pirates, everyone!
!قراصنةٌ يا جماعة
Pirates are coming!
!القراصنة قادمون
Pirates!
!قراصنة
Everyone hide!
!اختبؤوا جميعًا
It's the Arlong Pirates!
!إنهم قراصنة أرلونغ
Arlong?!
أرلونغ؟
That can't be!
!محال
Wh-What are fishmen from the Grand Line doing here?!
ما غاية مجيء برمائيين من الغراند لاين إلى هنا؟
Was the rumor about a split in the Fishman Pirates true?
أكانت إشاعةُ انفصالٍ في قراصنة البرمائيين صحيحة إذًا؟
Nami! Nojiko!
!نامي! نوجيكو
Mr. Gen!
!غين-سان
It's dangerous here!
!الوضع خطير هنا
Go and hide in the woods!
!اختبئا في الغابة الخلفية
Huh? But...
...ماذا؟ لكن
Go! Now!
!اذهبا حالًا
You seem to be in high spirits for a bunch of pathetic humans!
!تبدون بمعنويات ممتازة أيها البشر التافهون
As of this moment, this village– No, this entire island is under my control!
!ابتداءً من اليوم، هذه القرية، بل الجزيرة بأكملها تحت سيطرتنا
Listen up!
!اصغوا جيّدًا
On this glorious day, you will all buy your lives from me!
!في يومنا المنشود هذا، ستشترون حياتكم مني جميعًا
You'll pay 100,000 per adult.
مئة ألف بيري للبالغين
Each child is 50,000.
وخمسون ألفًا للصغار
Those who can't pay will die!
!ومن لا يدفع يهلك
What do we do, Nojiko?
ما العمل يا نوجيكو؟
We can't pay that much!
لا يُمكننا دفع هذا القدر
But they might not spot our house!
لكنهم قد لا يرصدون منزلنا
You can't see it from the village!
فإنه لا يُرى من القرية
How much did we get, brother?
كم كسبنا يا أخي؟
Just over 25 million, I'd say.
أكثر من 25 مليون برأيي
Excellent!
!ممتاز
Sounds like we have to pay 100,000 berries every month for the rest of our lives!
!يبدو أنّ علينا الدفع كل شهر مئة ألف بيري لبقية حياتنا
Pay 100,000...?! We can't even survive like that!
مئة ألف؟ ليس بوسعنا كسب قوت يومنا هكذا
Endure it for now!
!تحملوا حاليًّا
We should just be grateful no one in the village was killed.
علينا أن نسعد لعدم وجود ضحايا حتى الآن
If it's only money they want, that's an easy price to pay.
إن كان ما يريدونه هو المال فهذا ثمن سهل الدفع
I just hope they leave without seeing Bell-mère's house.
عساهم يغادرون دون رؤية منزل بيلمير
With the two children, it would come to 200,000 berries...
...مع حصة الطفلتين، سيصل المبلغ إلى مئتي مليون بيري
I doubt she has that much saved up.
أشكّ أنها ادخرت هذا القدر
Alright! Time to go, brothers!
!حسنٌ، فلنذهب يا إخوتي
Captain Arlong! There's smoke coming from over there!
!أرلونغ-سان، ثمة دخان صادر من خارج القرية
Okay!
!حسنٌ
Alright, let's see!
!حسنٌ، فلنرَ
That's too good! Nothing's quite like Bell-mère's special tangerine sauce!
لذيذ جدًا! لا شيء يضاهي صلصة بيلمير الخاصة لليوسفي
Nami and Nojiko are gonna leap out of their seats!
!ستقفزان نامي ونوجيكو من لذّته
The smoke is coming from a house!
!الدخان صادرٌ من هذا المنزل
Oh?
،عجبًا
We almost missed it.
كدنا نفوّته
Damn!
!سحقًا
– Bell-mère!
!بيلمير-سان
Come on! Let's go collect our money!
!هيا بنا، لنجمع مالنا
Oh no, this is bad! The pirates...
...هذا سيئ، إن القراصنة
...are headed to Bell-mère's house!
!متّهجون إلى منزل بيلمير...
Hey! Nojiko and Nami are gone!
!مهلًا، نوجيكو ونامي ليستا هُنا
What?!
ماذا؟
Ten more minutes for the duck in the oven.
عشر دقائق حتى يجهز البطّ في الفرن
The stew is boiling.
والحساء يغلي
This'll really mess up our budget,
،هذا سيفسد ميزانيتنا حقًّا
but sometimes you've gotta splurge!
لكن لا بُدَّ من الترف بين الحين والآخر
Bell-mère's gonna...
...بيلمير-سان... بيلمير-سان
Bell-mère's gonna be killed!
!بيلمير-سان ستُقتل
We can't just abandon Bell-mère!
!لا يمكننا أن نتخلى عن بيلمير
Damn! Why did this have to happen?!
سحقًا، لمَ آل الأمر لهذا؟
Don't jump the gun, Bell-mère!
!لا تتهوري يا بيلمير
Oh, are they back?
هل عادتا؟
It's open!
!إنه مفتوح
Come on in!
!ادخلا
Pardon me...
...المعذرة
You've got bad luck.
...مع الأسف
I'm a former Marine.
فقد كنتُ في البحرية
What are pirates from the Grand Line doing out here in Cocoyashi Village?
ما غاية مجيء قراصنة من الغراند لاين إلى قرية كوكوياشي؟
What's so funny?!
ما المضحك؟
Weak! Weak! You're weak! So weak! So, so weak!
!عاجزون! عاجزون! عاجزون! عاجزون! عاجزون
Your inferior species is just so weak!
!كم هو عاجزٌ جنسكم التافه
Let's escape with her out the back door!
!فلنهرب معها من الباب الخلفي
But they might already be there!
!لكنهم قد يكونون هناك سلفًا
We'll be fine!
!سنكون بخير
Hold it!
!انتظرا
Doctor!
!أيها الطبيب
You mustn't go home!
!لا ترجعا للمنزل
Wha...?!
...ما
Move! We have to save Bell-mère!
!تنحَّ، علينا إنقاذ بيلمير-سان
Nojiko! Nami!
!نوجيكو! نامي
Listen closely, you two!
!أصغيا جيّدًا
This isn't the time to–
...هذا ليس وقت أن
Actually, this is the perfect time...
...في الواقع، هذا الوقت المثالي
I have to tell you something horrible!
لأخبركما بأمرٍ فظيع
Doctor?
أيها الطبيب؟
Bell-mère!
!بيلمير-سان
I can't do anything! These guys are real monsters!
!لا فائدة، إنهم وحوشٌ حقيقيون
I'm gonna die!
!سأُقتل
Nojiko! Nami!
!نوجيكو! نامي
Bell-mère!
!بيلمير
Don't throw your life away over your pride!
!لا تهدري حياتكِ من أجلِ حسّ عدالة تافه
Some fights aren't worth it!
!بعض المعارك لا تستحقّ القتال
Some issues can be solved with money!
!ويمكن حلّ بعض المشكلات بالمال
Mr. Gen...
...غين-سان
That's right, Miss Marine.
هذا صحيح يا فتاة البحرية
It's 100,000 per adult and 50,000 per child.
مئة ألف للبالغين وخمسون ألفًا للأطفال
Pay for your whole family if you want to live. Be grateful I'm even telling you.
ادفعي لعائلتك إن أردتِ البقاء وعدّيني رحيمًا لأنني أخبرتك
My whole family?
عائلتي؟
That's 200,000 in total.
الإجمالي مئتا ألف
How much do you have, all together?
كم بحوزتكِ؟
Including what I've squirreled away...
...إن شملنا ما خبّأته
a little over 100,000...
...أكثر من مئة ألف بقليل
Hey! There's a meal for three people in here!
!اسمعوا، ثمّة عشاء لثلاثة أشخاص هنا
Oh?
ماذا؟
A family of three, huh?
عائلة من ثلاثة؟
I almost forgot!
!كدتُ أنسى
She invited my friend and me to dinner tonight!
!دعتني وصديقي للعشاء الليلة
Come on, Bell-mère.
هيا يا بيلمير
Hurry and pay your amount.
أسرعي وادفعي جزيتكِ
Our delicious dinner will get cold!
قبل أن يبرد طعامنا اللذيذ
Mr. Gen...
...غين-سان
I hear you've got 100,000.
سمعتُ أنّ بحوزتكِ مئة ألف
Thank goodness you have enough!
ارتاح بالي لحوزتكِ مبلغًا كافيًا
Now everyone in the village can live!
وبهذا نجا جميع أهل القرية
It's true.
...فعلًا
The village register has no record of her getting married or giving birth.
لم يُذكر في سجلّ القرية أنّها تزوجت أو أنجبت قبلًا
She's single.
إنها عزباء
Do you understand?!
أفهمتما؟
There's no proof that you two and Bell-mère are family!
!لا دليل على أنكما وبيلمير عائلة
Leave this island before they take notice of you!
!غادرا الجزيرة قبل أن يلاحظوكما
Escape across the sea!
!اهربا عبر البحر
Then all three of you can survive!
!هذه الطريقة الوحيدة لتنجون أنتنّ الثلاثة
It's reckless to send you two out to sea at such a young age.
طائشٌ إرسالكما إلى البحر في سنكما الصغير
A lot could go wrong, but at least you'll have–
قد تسوء الأمور أكثر، لكن على الأقل سيكون لديكما
No.
كلا
I don't want to.
لا أُريد ذلك
I... want to live in this village...
...أُريد... العيش في هذه القرية
Is it because we're poor?
ألِفُقرنا؟
Is that why we can't be Bell-mère's kids anymore?!
ألهذا لم نعد بنتا بيلمير؟
Why? Why?!
لماذا؟ لماذا؟
Thank goodness.
ارتاح بالي
Then everything will be fine.
ستنجوان بهذا
Alright, we'll leave the village!
فهمنا، سنغادر القرية
Nojiko!
!نوجيكو
Let's go!
!فلنذهب
This way Bell-mère gets to live!
ستعيش بيلمير هكذا
Hold it.
انتظرا
Who said I paid for myself?
من قال أني دفعت جزيتي؟
That 100,000 is for my two daughters.
هذه المئة ألف من أجل ابنتيَّ
Not for me.
ليست من أجلي
Bell-mère! What are you–
...بيلمير، ما الذي
I'm sorry, Mr. Gen.
اعذرني يا غين-سان
I can't just say I don't have a family.
...لا يُمكنني قول أن لا عائلة لي
Even if it costs me my life.
...ولو كلّفني ذلك حياتي
That fool...!
!يا للحماقة
Yeah, maybe we're not related by blood...
...قد لا تكون لدينا صلةٌ بالدم
but we're a family.
لكنّنا عائلة...
I want to be their mom, even if it's only in name.
أريد أن أكون أمّهما وإن كان ذلك بالاسم فحسب
They're...
...إنّهما
my girls.
...طفلتاي
– Bell-mère!
!بيلمير-سان
Wait, you two!
!انتظرا
I wish someone richer had adopted me instead!
!يا ليت أحدًا أغنى منكِ تبنّاني
It was just a lie!
!كانت مجرّد كذبة
I was lying!
!كنتُ أكذب
– Bell-mère!
!بيلمير-سان
I wanted...
...أردتُ
to buy you lots more books and clothes...
...أن أشتري لكما مزيدًا من الكتب والثياب
I'm sorry!
!اعذراني
I wish I could've been a better mother!
!عساني كنتُ أمًّا أفضل
That's not true!
!هذا غير صحيح
We don't need anything! Just don't die!
!لا نحتاج أيّ شيء، لا تموتي فحسب
Stay with us forever!
!ابقي معنا إلى الأبد
I want you to see the map of the world I'm gonna draw!
!أريدك أن تري خريطة العالم التي سأرسمها
Yeah... your map...
...نعم... خريطتكِ
Make your dream...
...حققي
come true!
...حلمكِ
Live!
!عيشي
Bell-mère!
!بيلمير-سان
These are your girls, I take it?
أرى أنهما ابنتاكِ؟
Yeah, that's right!
!نعم، هذا صحيح
Promise me you won't lay a hand on them!
!عدني أنّكم لن تمسّوهما بسوء
Of course!
!أكيد
As long as you follow the rules and die!
!ما دمتِ ستموتين بطوع
Help us!
!النجدة
Now they're thirsty for blood...
...باتوا متعطّشين للدماء الآن
Don't kill them. Just handle them as you see fit.
لا تقتلوهم، تعاملوا معهم كما ترونه مناسبًا
Perfect timing for our first example to the others!
!إنهُ توقيتٌ ممتاز لنضرب مثلنا الأول للناس
Die for your worthless love.
موتي مع حبّكِ التافه
Nojiko! Nami!
!نوجيكو! نامي
I love you!
!أحبّكما